Moki Daniel Mathuva Software Engineer/ Sales Executive Email: mokidnl@gmail.com

Address: 5-90220 Kyatune Kitui Kenya

Nationality: Kenyan **Phone:** (254) 736334075 **Date of Birth:** 1988-06-01

Personal Website: https://moki-daniel.github.io/portfolio/ **Linked-in:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/moki-daniel-47243159/

GitHub: https://github.com/moki-daniel

Facebook: https://web.facebook.com/dev.moki.77/

Career Objective

Passionate Software Engineering professional, who has 7 years and 10 months experience in the Information technology industry, five years and seven months involved in support of hardware, networking and software of on-premise infrastructure while two years and three months in software development. Currently much involved in web development and cloud Devops engineering. Aspire to be a great technical leader who is able to solve real world challenges in an efficient and professional manner using technology.

Experience

Remote Software Engineer Freelance January 2018 to Present

Territory Sales Executive Fine Media Kenya Limited Nairobi, Kenya November 2019 to Present

Information Technology Assistant Dac Aviation International Nairobi, Kenya November 2015 to December 2017

System Technician Fincom Technologies Limited Nairobi, Kenya. June 2014 to October 2015 Develop and deploy websites using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript. Currently learning ReactJS, nodeJS and Amazon Web Services for improved Software development and cloud deployments.

Recruit and manage Airtel Money agents, Sim Selling outlets and franchise Shops on behalf of Airtel Kenya. Ensure increased sales of Airtel products in Matiliku territory, based in Makueni County Kenya.

Supported the organizations infrastructure, this included hardware, Software and Networking of the organization.

Managed Aviation based Information Management Systems including Pentagon, Dragon, Navigator and Microsoft products.

Supported hardware and software sections of the co-operate clients of Fincom Technologies Limited, this involved Servers, computers, printers and cheaque Scanner repairs, Windows server configurations, general software installations and network cabling.

Software Engineer Circuit Business Systems Limited Nairobi, Kenya March 2013 to April 2014 Supported AMLIB, A library management system installed in different Cooperate organizations in East Africa by Circuit Business Systems. I was involved in training users, installing the system on new users data centers, software documentation for new modules or changes in the system, creating crystal reports and did database configurations for both MySQL and Oracle database Management system this involved data mining, space management and database tuning during system falls

Intern IT Department Circuit Business Systems Limited Nairobi, Kenya April 2014 to November 2014 Trained as a Support Engineer for hardware and software section of Information Technology. Through this period I learned much on managing existing Information Management System, repairing and configuring computers, Servers and Printers.

Intern Network Operation Center Jamii Telecommunicatins Limited Nairobi, Kenya May 2010 to August 2010 Trained on Network operation center (NOC) services especially online activity monitoring of clients links, Problem and event ticketing, Remote event management for satellite, Wimax and fiber clients, Initial support on IP configuration for link commissioning and implementation and fiber network path survey and network termination

Intern Networking Department Kenya Airways Limited Nairobi, Kenya May 2009 to August 2009 Trained on Network department management in a big organization, this includes switch and router configurations, routing and re-routing of both data and voice signals, CAT6 splicing and security management in big data centers.

Education

Bachelor Level Diploma Front-End Development OpenClassrooms International April 2020 to April 2021 Student at openClassrooms International Front-End Developer path from April 2020 to April 2021. The courses and projects teach web development using Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Wordpress, reactJS and MySQL Link for the school https://openclassrooms.com/en/dashboard

Bachelor Level Diploma Cloud Devops Engineer Udacity March 2020 to September 2020 Currently undertaking Cloud Devops Engineer course with a specialization in Amazon Web Services at Udacity started on March 2020 and will finish on September 2020. Link for the school: https://www.udacity.com/

Bsc. Information Science Moi University August 2008 to December 2012 Studied a Bsc. Information Science at Moi University, where I attained a Second Class Honors Upper Division from August 2008 to December 2012 with a specialization in Information Technology.

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education Kitui School February 2003 to December 2007 Studied at Kitui High School for a Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education and attained a mean grade of B plain Subjects: Mathematics, English, Kiswahili, Geography, Physics, Biology, Chemistry and Computer Studies. Kenya Certificate of Primary

Education

St Josephs Boarding Primary

School

January 1999 to December 2002

Attained a Certificate in Primary Education with a mean grade of B plus. Subjects: Mathematics, Science, English, Kiswahili and

Social Studies.

Skills

Front End Developer Ability to develop websites using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript

Cloud Devops Engineer Ablility to deploy websites to the cloud using Amazon Web

Services

Microsoft Products Ablility to manage and support Microsoft Office packages,

Windows Server and office 365.

Networking Ability to configure routers, switches and wireless network

resources. Splice cat6 network cables and manage on-premise and

hybrid data centers.

References

1) Kevin Tendwa

Treasury Accountant, Mantrac Limited

Phone-number: (254)716217507 E-mail: <u>ktendwa@mantrackenya.com</u>

2) Nixon Namayi

Business Development Manager

JoWorld Limited

Phone-number: (254)721464194 E-mail: <u>nixon@joworld.co.ke</u>

3) Cliff Gor

Former Lead Program Assistant DevcTrainingWithAndela Phone-number: 0712796467 Email: <u>cliffordgor@hotmail.com</u>